<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Techpression</title>
    <link href="https://enhasa666.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://enhasa666.github.io" />
    <updated>2019-07-25T18:49:07+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Enhasa</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://enhasa666.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Speeding Up Windows 10</title>
        <author>
            <name>Enhasa</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://enhasa666.github.io/speeding-up-windows-10.html"/>
        <id>https://enhasa666.github.io/speeding-up-windows-10.html</id>

        <updated>2019-07-25T18:49:02+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Depending on who you ask, Windows 10 is either the best operating system to date, or the worst hunk of garbage that has ever graced their computer. It’s really not hard to see why the reception of this operating system is so polarized: Windows 10&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p id="mcetoc_1dgkbjon80">Depending on who you ask, Windows 10 is either the best operating system to date, or the worst hunk of garbage that has ever graced their computer.</p>
<p>It’s really not hard to see why the reception of this operating system is so polarized: Windows 10 has brought about so many great features like multiple desktops (something Linux users has had for two decades), improved driver autodetection,  Continuum (for those with hybrid devices), a simplified/unified settings panel that helps out 10% of the time, and a bunch more I couldn’t care less about.</p>
<p>On the flip side, Windows 10 (actually, since Windows 7) brought about forced updates and reboots, and a steady stream of additional features that, instead of helping out the user keep the system in perfect working order or assist in the most menial of tasks, hammered the operating system disk with non-essential background tasks that kept reading and writing to drive c.</p>
<p>These updates essentially make Windows 10 unusable on systems with slow storage. 100% disk usage makes the whole desktop and every other application unresponsive as fuck, and updates either hammer the disk usage themselves while downloading or take 45 minutes to an hour to install packages. For the latter case, I even witnessed that happen at work when I was still employed at some cheapskate marketing company.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dgkbkk5l1">The fix</h2>
<p>Jesus Christ. Just get a fucking SSD.</p>
<p>Whether you are on a laptop or a desktop, or whether you have a spare drive slot or not, there is simply no excuse for not having an SSD installed.</p>
<p>240GB SSDs are fucking cheap. If you’re on a laptop and you need large storage capacities, external hard drive enclosures are also fucking cheap – just slap your laptop’s old hard drive in there and you’re good to go. Stop wasting your time waiting for Windows to “start being ready to launch apps”. Stop wasting your time waiting for the <em>Downloads</em> folder to complete listing its contents. Stop wasting your time trying to figure out why the fuck your laptop is running extremely hot, even though you have reinstalled Windows a fuck-ton of times and are absolutely sure you’re not running any bloatware whatsoever.</p>
<p>Online guides will tell you to turn off all visual effects, run disk cleanup, defragment, disable startup programs, turn off Cortana and search indexing, and all sorts of bullshit. Those won’t do jack, because (a) your problem is not the lack of processing power, and (b) these services don’t gobble up disk usage as much as you’d think.</p>
<p>Even if you’re rocking an i69s-6969K your anemic hard drive will hold you back. The CPU simply can’t do shit if it can’t get the data off your hard drive. No OS reinstall will fix that.</p>
<p>240GB SSDs are 25 USD. How much is your time worth, really? Is your time really worth being spent on following some guy’s tutorial on the internet, whose sole motivation “to help you” is ad revenue from the ads and trackers peppered across his site?</p>
<p>Give it a shot. Get an SSD and install it yourself or have someone do it for you. Bam. Problems solved.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dgkbld342">Spreading the word</h2>
<p>Let’s assume that someone actually came into my blog, read this post, and changed his mind and got himself an SSD. He’s probably so stoked about how much a small credit card-sized thing fixed all his problems with his computer that he wants to tell all his friends about it. He’d want to preach the word of the SSD, and how it will save us from the evil productivity killer called the mechanical hard drive.</p>
<p>If you’re someone like the above hypothetical guy, I’m going to tell you straight away that there is no point trying to get people to switch to SSDs. They simply won’t care – even if they do, it’s extremely hard to quantify the performance gains of an SSD. It’s not like this is a processor where you can give it a core count or a clock speed to compare speeds with – storage options are being discussed in terms of capacity and not much else. Ah yes, capacity – good luck getting past the “capacity downgrade” argument that is always raised during these conversations.</p>
<p>So unless you’re head of IT or a tech-savvy business operations manager who gives a shit about office productivity, just shut it and enjoy watching other people struggle getting shit done on HDDs.</p>
<p>You’re not changing anyone’s minds. Hell, even performance comparisons between SSDs and HDDs on YouTube have been received positively only by those already on SSDs. The results have been completely ignored by those “smart enough not to buy something overpriced that holds much fewer data”.</p>
<p>Much like everything else, storage capacity discussions are avenue for dick-measuring contests. By going with SSDs, you’ll have the smaller dick, and nobody really wants that - even if you’re able to thrust magnitudes faster than the other bros.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Start A Blog</title>
        <author>
            <name>Enhasa</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://enhasa666.github.io/how-to-start-a-blog.html"/>
        <id>https://enhasa666.github.io/how-to-start-a-blog.html</id>

        <updated>2019-07-21T15:43:54+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Starting a blog is one of the most popular avenues for creative expression today. It is relatively easy to do, free on most cases even if you don't know where to look, and virtually friction-free when getting your content out to the hands of your&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Starting a blog is one of the most popular avenues for creative expression today. It is relatively easy to do, free on most cases even if you don't know where to look, and virtually friction-free when getting your content out to the hands of your readers.</p>
<p>I will say this right off the bat: self-publishing and promotion is easy, but that doesn't mean you're going to get readers into your blog. In fact, you probably won't.</p>
<p>Unless you're dedicated to writing good-vibes bullshit for years on end, or are spamming other bloggers' comments section in hopes that they comment back on your blog, you're literally just a tiny speck of sand in the desert that is the internet that everyone will ignore.</p>
<p>But don't let this faze you! If you want to do something - like start a blog - fucking do it. Don't let the fact that your efforts will probably go unnoticed stop you from doing something different with your life. And think about it: if you vent your anger off somewhere else on the far reaches of the internet, you'll save yourself from the social suicide you will <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">probably most likely</span> surely commit on Facebook or Twitter.</p>
<p>Ready to pull the hopefully-metaphorical trigger?</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dg98e8fb0">Easy steps to start a blog</h2>
<p><strong>Step one is the hardest for most people</strong> - it was for me.</p>
<p>Before you start doing anything, you're going to have to accept that you're not a special cookie. Your unorthodox opinions do not make you unique, as you probably have them just because they're wildly different from those of your peers.</p>
<p>Even if your world views were actually as cool as you think they were, then why aren't you talking about it on TED Talks or some shit? What credentials do you have that we must listen to you as you assert some radical crap that no one will (or no one will want to) listen to? </p>
<p>Consider this: global warming is an undeniable phenomena confirmed by thousands of brilliant scientists around the world, and even they are brushed off by the general population. This group of brilliant scientists have years of experience and research behind them - not to mention they are <em>genuinely intelligent</em> - yet we cover our ears as we're fed the 10000th warning that humanity will fall under its own weight if we don't do something about it.</p>
<p>We continue to purchase gargantuan SUVs - a purchase justified by the coming of a couple's first baby, of course - and ignore warnings of humanity's impending doom. What makes you think "your audience" is going to do any different and actually listen to you?</p>
<p><em>The first step to start a blog, then, is to accept that no one will bother reading your work</em>. Just write as you would like to write and enjoy the process. </p>
<p>No matter well you write it, or how dedicated you are to editing it to make sure you're writing effectively, nobody will appreciate it. No matter how sound an argument you make, you're not changing anyone's minds. </p>
<p>Who cares? Why does it matter anyway? You're going to be nobody forever and there's nothing you can do to change that.</p>
<p>Just do it.</p>
<p><strong>With step two, things begin to get a lot easier</strong>.</p>
<p>Get yourself a good blogging platform. I would recommend something like <a href="https://wordpress.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WordPress</a> or <a href="https://www.blogger.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Blogger</a>, as they are the two most popular services out there. They're so reliable that I could even imagine their servers continuing to run even amidst a global cataclysm that I think couldn't come any sooner.</p>
<p>Note: I would recommend something like <a href="https://www.wix.com">Wix </a>or similar graphical website builders, but I personally have no experience with them and they seem like they have more features than the regular blogger would need. </p>
<p><strong>Step three: create an account and start posting.</strong></p>
<p>That's it! You can now start writing content that will most definitely not be read by anyone ever! Well, maybe your chosen platform's content moderators will, but they will forget about it seconds after as they move through their thousands-long moderation queue, after which you have passed you will become nothing more but a mere statistic.</p>
<p>Have fun!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
